<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Taraba State</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="agric">The major occupation of the people of Taraba State is agriculture. Cash crops produced in the state include coffee, tea, groundnuts and cotton. Crops such as maize, rice, sorghum, millet, cassava, and yam are also produced in commercial quantity. In addition, cattle, sheep and goats are reared in large numbers, especially on the Mambilla Plateau, and along the Benue and Taraba valleys. Similarly, the people undertake other livestock production activities like poultry production, rabbit breeding and pig farming in fairly large scale. Communities living on the banks of River Benue, River Taraba, River Donga and Ibi engage in fishing all year round. Other occupational activities such as pottery, cloth-weaving, dyeing, mat-making, carving, embroidery and blacksmithing are also carried out in various parts of the State.</string>
    <string name="culture">The government has made concerted efforts to improve areas of tourist attractions like Mambilla Tourist Center, Gumpti Park and game reserve in Gashaka; and the Nwunyu Fishing festival in Ibi, which is usually held in April of each year where activities such as canoe racing, swimming competition and cultural dances are held. Other festivals are Purma of the Chamba in Donga, Takum and jibu culture dance in Bali, the Puje of Jukuns, Kuchecheb of Kutebs in Takum and Ussa, Kati of the Mambilla and host of others. Taraba is called \'Nature\'s gift to the nation\' as the state is rich and have many ethnic groups, including Jenjo, jibawa, Kuteb Chamba, Yandang, Mumuyes, Mambila, Wurkums, Fulanis, Jukun,Ichen,Tiv,Kaka, Hausa and Ndola. A striking historical fact about the State is that it encompasses part of the Mambilla Region which is famed as the Bantu cradle, having been occupied for some five millennia to date (Schwartz, 1972; Zeitlyn and Connell, 2003).</string>
    <string name="geography">"Taraba State is bounded in the west by Nasarawa State and Benue State, northwest by Plateau State, north by Bauchi State and Gombe State, northeast by Adamawa State, south and east by Cameroon.

Taraba State lies largely within the middle of Nigeria and consists of undulating landscape dotted with a few mountainous features. These include the scenic and prominent Mambilla Plateau. The state lies largely within the tropical zone and has a vegetation of low forest in the southern part and grassland in the northern part. The Mambilla Plateau with an altitude of 1,800 meters (6000 ft) above sea level has a temperate climate all year round.

Rivers Benue, Donga, Taraba and Ibi are the main rivers in the state. They rise from the Cameroonian mountains, straining almost the entire length of the state in the North and South direction to link up with the River Niger."</string>

    <string name="history">"The state was created out of the former Gongola State on 27 August 1991, by the military government of General Ibrahim Babangida.
        Taraba State was created on August 27th, 1991 out of the defunct Gongola State. Aptly christened ‘Nature’s Gift to the Nation’, Taraba state is a reservoir of natural resources capable of promoting the storied greatness of the nation if carefully harnessed. Its vast natural potentials can be classified under agriculture, mineral deposit and tourism.

        The name, Taraba, was derived from the Taraba River, which traverses the southern part of the State. Other main rivers in the State are Ibi, Donga and Benue, which all rise from the Cameroon Mountains, stretching almost the entire length of the state in the Northern and the Southern direction to link up with the River Niger.

The state is made up of sixteen (16) Local Government Areas and a Special Development Area. These areas constitute administrative units in three geopolitical zones with a total population of three (3) million people.

The three geopolitical zones are northern senatorial zone, central senatorial zone and southern senatorial zone.

The Northern Senatorial Zone is made up of Jalingo (which is also the state capital), Zing, Ardo-Kola, Lau, Karim-Lamido and Yorro Local Government Areas. The Central Senatorial Zone is made up of Bali, Gashaka, Kurmi, Gassol and Sardauna Local Government Areas.  The Southern Senatorial Zone include Donga, Takum, Ibbi, Ussa and Wukari Local Government Areas plus Yangtu Special Development area.

With a landmass of 59,400 Square kilometers, the State lies roughly between latitudes 6.30 and 9.36 North and longitudes 9.10 and 11.50 East.

Lying in the North-East geopolitical region of Nigeria, Taraba State shares common boundaries with Bauchi and Gombe State to the North, Adamawa State to the North-East, Plateau State to the West and Benue state to the South-West and Eastern part of the State. It also shares International Boundaries with the Republic of Cameroun to the Southern and Eastern parts of the state.

Going by ethnological composition, Taraba State has over 200 ethnic grounds. Chiefly among them include Mambilla, Chamba, Jukun, Fulani, Tiv, Ichen, Jenjo, Kuteb, Mumuye, Hausa, Munga, Wurkun, Yandang, Kabawa and Karimjo. Others are Bandawa, Kaka, Bambuka, Kambu, Zo, Kunini, Loo, Ndoro, Panso, Shomo and Tigun. Taraba State is the microcosm of the Nigerian nation.

The State’s topography comprises undulating plains and rising hills with five vegetative zones unique to it throughout the whole country. These diverse five vegetations are:

1. Sudan Savannah,
2. Guinea Savannah,
3. Derived Savannah,
4. High Forest and
5. Mountain Forest.
"</string>
    <string name="senators_list">Sen. Sani Abubakar Danladi Sen. Yusuf Abubakar Yusuf, Sen. Emmanuel Bwacha</string>


    <string name="gumpti_details">"Gashaka-Gumti National Park is located in a mountainous region of North-east Nigeria adjacent to the international border with Cameroon, and immediately to the North of the Mambilla plateau. No roads cross this remote region and only a few lonely footpaths wind through the forested mountains towards Cameroon. Visitors to the park are able to enjoy lush forests, wide sweeping grasslands, cool highland plateaus, rugged moody mountains, abundant wildlife, and fascinating ethnic cultures, all combined within a single protected area. There are few other places in the world that contain such spectacular scenery and such diverse wildlife. The hidden corner of west Africa that is Gashaka-Gumti National Park is surely one of the continent's best kept secrets.

Gashaka-Gumti National Park, the largest park in Nigeria, covers 6,731 sq km of wilderness. The park's name is derived from two of the region's oldest and most historic settlements: Gashaka village in Taraba State, and Gumti village in Adamawa State. Gashaka-Gumti National Park was created by Federal Decree in 1991 by the merging of Gashaka Game Reserve with Gumti Game Reserve. In this guidebook we will use the term Gashaka sector to indicate the Southern half of the park, and the term Gumti sector to indicate the Northern half.

The Northern, Gumti sector of the park is relatively flat and covered with woodlands and grasslands, whilst the Southern, Gashaka sector is more mountainous and contains vast expanses of rainforest as well as areas of woodlands and montane grassland. This rugged terrain is characterised by steep, thickly forested slopes, deep plunging valleys, precipitous escarpments and swiftly flowing rivers. Altitude ranges from 450 metres above sea level in the wild savannah plains of the Northern sector, to the peaks and pinnacles of Gangirwal in the Southern park sector, which at a staggering 2,400 metres above sea level, represents Nigeria's highest mountain.

It boasts of the best mountain ranges in Nigeria. The Gumti sector of the park is relatively flat and covered with woodlands and grasslands, whilst the southern Gashaka sector is more mountainous and contains vast expanses of rainforest as well as areas of woodlands and mountain grassland. This rugged terrain is characterised by steep, thickly forested slopes, deep plunging valleys, precipitous escarpments and swiftly flowing rivers. It stands at 450 metres above sea level in the wild savannah plains of the Northern sector, while the peaks of Chappal Waddi (meaning the mountain of death) in the Southern park sector rise to a staggering 2,400 metres or 7,936 feet above sea level. You are likely to find Nigeria’s highest mountain here.

It is the sheer variety of different habitats that makes the park so uniquely rich in wildlife. In fact, the park is actually an intricate mosaic of mountain grasslands, savannah woodlands, swamps, lakes, mighty rivers, dark lowland rainforests, and luxuriant, mountain rainforests strewn with ferns and orchids. Each habitat supports its own distinctive community of plants and animals. "</string>
    <string name="gashaka_details2">"Rainforests provide a haven for animals such as the giant forest hog, leopard, yellow-backed duiker, golden cat, and many different primate species including chimpanzees. Woodland savannahs are home to buffalos, lions, elephants, wild dogs, as well as various antelopes such as waterbucks, including roan antelopes, cob, hartebeest and the world’s largest antelope, the Giant eland.

The mountains of the park harbour populations of the rare Adamawa mountain reedbuck, in addition to black-and-white monkey specie, baboon, warthog and klipspringer, while its largest un-spoilt rivers contain hippos, crocodiles, others and a wide variety of fishes. The park is officially labelled one of Africa’s "important bird areas" - and with more than 500 species found here, this is certainly no exaggeration as visiting bird watchers constantly add new species to their existing lists.

Gashaka-Gumti National Park is located in a mountainous region of North-East Nigeria adjacent to the international border with Cameroun, and immediately to the North of the Mambilla plateau. No roads cross this remote region and only a few lonely footpaths wind through the forested mountains towards Cameroun.

Visitors to the park are able to enjoy lush forests, wide sweeping grasslands, cool highland plateaus, rugged moody mountains, abundant wildlife, and fascinating ethnic cultures, all combined within a single protected area, which is larger than two states in Nigeria. There are few places in the world that contain such a spectacular scenery and such diverse wildlife. The hidden corner of West Africa that is Gashaka-Gumti National Park is surely one of the continent’s best kept secrets. "</string>
    <string name="mambilla_details">"Located in the highland region of Taraba State of Nigeria, Mambilla Plateau houses Chappal Waddi mountain considered the highest point in Nigeria with an average height of about 2,419 metres (7,936 ft) above sea level.

As a destination it has one of the best weather conditions in the country which is cool and always accommodating all year round, unlike other parts of the country where there are temperature extremes during the day and night. The Mambilla Plateau is also free of mosquitoes and tse-tse flies. Daytime temperature hardly exceed 25°C on Mambilla; the driest months are from December to January with relative humidity dropping to about 15 per cent while the wet season usually starts from August.

Just as the weather is accommodating, so also are the people of the Mambilla Plateau, welcoming and so hospitable. At an altitude of some 700m, these villagers live in a different ecological zone where oil palms grow and gallery forest is found. The Mambilla language is an amalgam of dialects and related languages. Beauty of the plateau The journey to Mambilla starts on a snake-like road from the foot of the mountain to the top, about 25 to 30 minutes drive where you start savouring the beauty of the plateau.

There are rolling hills, backdropped with exotic flora and fauna. It has a lot of scenic views to behold, which while watching the mountain chain and the curvacious valleys you will have a breath of fresh air that is uncommon in many other parts of Nigeria.
"</string>

    <string name="mambilla_details2">"The major tourism attraction sites on the plateau are: The mountain chain, the plain green view, and a magnificent water fall. Then there is the historic site — the famous cave in Mbamnga — Ndumyaji Cave. There is the rock with a giant foot print of an ancient warrior at Kabri, the rock with a horse foot print at Hienary, the historic site of the ancient blacksmith that existed before the modern one at Killa yang.

It also has the second largest tea plantation in the world second to the one in India. Livestock like cow, goats, sheep and other rare birds thrive on the plateau. There are also natural forests like the Ngel Yaki mountain forest and the Ndum-yaji forest that are home to very rare species of birds and trees which have attracted lots of researchers from around the world.

Because of the remote location of the plateau and lack of properly tarred roads which are still under construction, utility vehicles are recommended and visitors should make sure that essential camping equipment and food are included in their journey.
"</string>

    <string name="marmara_details">The Marmara crocodile pond is situated in Wukari and reputed to be an ancient pond full of legendary crocodiles which are largely sighted on Fridays.

There is a fable making the rounds that these crocs in ancient times went into town to pay homage to Aku Uka, the supreme head of the Jukuns.

If you’re ever in Taraba State, then you mustn’t leave until you’ve seen these legendary crocs that live at peace with animals and humans without hurting anyone. </string>
    <string name="ngel_details">"The Ngel-Nyaki Forest Reserve is nearly 60 kilometres west of Gashaka-Gumti National Park, and it is much closer to Yelwa in situated between Serti and Gembu.

There are over 50 species of tall, emergent trees in this forest reserve, and you stand a chance of seeing the 86 bird species which have made this reserve their eternal home.

Wild creatures to see at this forest reserve include Apalis, banner man’s weaver, cross ley’s ground thrust, chimpanzees, buffalos, various monkeys, antelops and other attractive creatures. "</string>
    <string name="nba_kati_details">Nba Kati is celebrated annually around November/December by the inhabitants of the Sardauna LGA. It is a mourning festival for those who have died during the year. During the festival, newly-married couples come out to receive blessings and consult the gods.</string>

    <string name="nwonyo_fishing_details">"Historical Background
Nwonyo Fishing and Cultural Festival is said to be one of the oldest of its kind in Africa. The festival started about 96 years ago and is usually held at the Nwonyo Lake, located some five kilometres north of Ibi town. The name “Nwonyo” literally means “a hideout” for monstrous aquatic animals such as crocodiles and hippopotamus. This meaning was derived from the fact that the Nwonyo creek contains a variety of these aquatic animals. However, there are two myths surrounding the actual meaning of the word Nwonyo. The first version says it means, “under the locust bean tree;” while the second version says, “abode of the snake,” in Jukun language. The Nwonyo Lake is said to be the largest in West Africa, running a stretch of about 15 kilometres tributary to the River Benue. According to oral tradition, the lake was discovered by Bula (in Wuroboh language) a great descendant of the Jibu dynasty who was sent to Ibi to look after activities carried out by traders around the river. Bula discovered that the lake was more than a source of fish supply; he then transformed the large scale fishing activity into a fishing festival by members of Ibi Community. This transformation began in 1826. During his reign, communities living around Nwonyo Lake were invited to the lake to catch fish once in every year. The catch made was then divided into three portions; and because of his liberal nature, Bulah would take one portion only and give the remaining two portions to the fishermen.

Features of the Festival
It could be said that over the years, the Nwonyo Fishing Festival has assumed a different dimension, incorporating various activities. Some of these include:
*Boat Racing
*Swimming
*Boat Regatta
*Masquerade Dances
*Traditional Dances
*The Fish-Catch Competition (main event)

The fish-catch competition is the main event of the festival. Masquerading, traditional dances, horse riding/racing, boat racing, swimming, and boat regatta are the recreational/entertainment activities that take place during the festival. The Chief of Ibi is the custodian of the festival; while the “Sarkin Ruwa” (spiritual head of the Nwonyo Lake) is the overseer of the lake. He patrols the lake with his guards on regular basis because nobody is allowed to fish in the lake for a period of one year before the event and one week after the event. The lake is closed to fishermen to allow the fish in it grow and mature for the next festival season. The Sarkin Ruwa also performs certain traditional rites along with the custodian at the river before the commencement of every fishing competition. The fishermen (competitors) can only go into the river when it has been declared open by him. Wide and big fishing nets are used for the fishing competition and most of the fishing efforts are in groups. The biggest catch is said to be known as the “Giwan Ruwa.” At the end of the festival, prizes are given to the first three persons with the biggest catch. The catches are in turn auctioned while others are sold to dignitaries, spectators, and participants at the event. "</string>
    <string name="other_tourist">" TOURIST ATTRACTIONS AREAS IN TARABA STATE

1. The temperate climate of the famous Mambilla Plateau Gembu, Sardauna L.G.A.
2. Barup waterfalls – Gembu, Sardauna L.G.A.
3. Kakara Tea Plantation and Factory- Gembu Sardauna L.G.A.
4. Tunga Dam (Man-made) – Gembu, Sardauna L.G.A.
5. Gashaka Gumti National Park- Serti, Gashaka L.G.A.
6. Kashimbila Dam (Man –Made)-Takum, Takum L.G.A.
7. Rock formations at Fikyu-Ussa L.G.A.
8. Rock formations at Kpambo-Ussa L.G.A.
9. Marmara crocodile Pond Wukari, Wukari L.G.A.
10. Highest Point in Nigeria at Chappal wadi (Mountain of death)-Gembu, Sardauna L.G.A.
11. Nwonyo fishing and Cultural Festival-Ibi, Ibi L.G.A.
12. Pre-Colonial Executive pit- Ibi, Ibi L.G.A.
13. Colonial Burial Ground- Ibi,Ibi L.G.A.
14. Barite Quary – Ibi, Ibi L.G.A.
15. Rock formation at Zing –Zing L.G.A.
16. Rock Formations at Bitako-Zing L.G.A."</string>

    <string name="cutural_festivals">"1. MINHU Hunting Festival – held in Jen Karim- Lamido L.G.A. April Yearly.

2. Kachicheb Harvest Festival – Ussa/ Takum L.G.A.s normally held on 25th March each year.

3. Puje Festival Normally held in Wukari Yearly and during the installation of a new Aku- Uka.

4. Purma/ Takachiyawa / Takum/ Donga Normally held between November and December yearly by the Chambas.

5. Belle Festival Zing Local Government Marking the beginning of a new planting season.

6. Yonko- Yam Festival.it is celebrated by the Mumuye Nation to mark the harvest / consumption of new yams.

7. Kati harvest Festival Sardauna November Yearly.

8. Kambu/Panso Cultural Festival – Sardauna L.G.A.

9. Ekpan- Fure Jukun Festival – Takum/ Wukari

10. Asamu Festival in Kona- Jalingo Local Government Area."</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ads">Ads</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="interstitial_ad_sample">Interstitial Ad Sample</string>
    <string name="start_level">Level 1</string>
    <string name="next_level">Next Level</string>
    <!-- -
            This is an ad unit ID for an interstitial test ad. Replace with your own interstitial ad unit id.
            For more information, see https://support.google.com/admob/answer/3052638
        <!- -->
    <string name="interstitial_ad_unit_id">ca-app-pub-3940256099942544/1033173712</string>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id">ca-app-pub-9011126165883524/2135914890</string>

    <string name="afolahm_name">Adeyemi Afolahan</string>
    <string name="afolaham_details">"Rear Admiral (retired) Adeyemi Ambrose Afolahan (born 26 December 1949) was appointed the first Administrator of Taraba State, Nigeria in August 1991 after the state was created from part of the old Gongola State during the military regime of General Ibrahim Babangida. He handed over to the elected civilian governor Jolly Nyame in January 1992 at the start of the Nigerian Third Republic.

Afolahan was born on 26 December 1949 in Ibadan, Oyo State. He studied in Nigeria and the United Kingdom. Posts included deputy commandant, National War College, Abuja, Chief of Naval Operations and Chief of Naval Plans.

Speaking at a seminar in Lagos in May 2000, Afolahan called on Nigerian youths to abstain from sex or at least use condoms to ensure an AIDS-free society. He became Chairman of the Ila Orangun Unity Movement."</string>

    <string name="jolly_nyame_name">Jolly Nyame</string>
    <string name="jolly_nyame_details_first">"Jolly Tavoro Nyame (born 25 December 1955 in the Zing Local Government Area of present-day Taraba State) was Governor of Taraba State in Nigeria from 29 May 1999 to 29 May 2007. He also served as governor of the state from January 1992 to November 1993. He is a member of the then ruling People's Democratic Party "</string>

    <string name="yohanna_dickson">Yohanna Dickson</string>

    <string name="yohanna_dickson_details">"Colonel (retired) Yohanna Mamman Dickson (28 December 1950 – 14 July 2015) was Administrator of Taraba State, Nigeria from December 1993 to August 1996 during the military regime of General Sani Abacha.

In April 2001, Dickson was named a member of the steering committee of the newly formed United Nigeria Development Forum (UNDF), a political group headed by several former military governors. In the April 2003 elections, Dickson was an unsuccessful candidate running on the United Nigeria People's Party (UNPP) platform for the Kaduna South senatorial seat.

Dickson challenged the result, saying the winner, Isaiah Balat of the People's Democratic Party (PDP), was not qualified to run for election.

Dickson later transferred to the PDP. In January 2009 he was appointed chairman of a seven-member disciplinary committee of the Kaduna State PDP chapter. He was appointed chairman of the Kaduna State Water Board. In August 2009, while inspecting a new water supply in the Zaria Regional Water Supply Scheme, Dickson said that the state would deal severely with contractors who failed to deliver on schedule and according to specifications.

Dickson died on 14 July 2015, aged 64, in Kaduna State, Nigeria"</string>

    <string name="amen">Amen Edore Oyakhire</string>

    <string name="amen_details">"Prince Amen Edore Oyakhire was the Military Administrator of Taraba State, Nigeria between August 1996 and August 1998 during the military regime of General Sani Abacha. He was then administrator of Oyo State during the transitional regime of General Abdulsalami Abubakar, handing over to the elected civilian governor Lam Onaolapo Adesina in May 1999 at the start of the Nigerian Fourth Republic.

Police career[edit]
Oyakhire was a commissioner of police, later an Assistant Inspector General (AIG) He was the Police Commissioner, Plateau State Command before being appointed administrator of Taraba State.

In Taraba State, Oyakhire had to deal with hostilities between the Kuteb and Chamba and Jukun ethnic groups. In October 1997 he sent a paper called Comprehensive brief on the Chieftaincy Stool of Takum Chiefdom Taraba State to the Armed Forces Ruling Council. That month seven people were killed and seven houses razed in communal violence, and 31 people were arrested. Oyakhire said anyone suspected of involvement in the communal violence would be treated as detractors of the transition to civil rule. In 1998 the Taraba State Government also set up a Peace Committee which managed to negotiate a temporary peace between the ethnic groups.

Shortly before the handover to civilian government in May 1999, Oyakhire told a U.S. Embassy observer team that "Power is to be handed over to credible people who have the fear of God in their hearts, and this will ensure the stability of the nation"."</string>

    <string name="awoniyi">Aina Owoniyi</string>

    <string name="awoniyi_details">"Colonel (retired) Aina Joseph Owoniyi was Administrator of Taraba State, Nigeria from August 1998 to May 1999 during the transitional regime of General Abdulsalami Abubakar.

Owoniyi's administration was notable for lack of corruption. He approved salary increases for Taraba State Civil Servants. In November 1998 Owoniyi suspended indefinitely the Commissioner of Agriculture Daniel Nyaa Bobzom and his Education counterpart Joseph Rishante for insubordination, negligence of duty and sabotage. After handing over to the civilian governor Jolly Nyame in May 1999, as a former military administrator he was required to retire from the army."</string>

    <string name="jolly">Jolly Nyame</string>

    <string name="jolly_details">"Jolly Tavoro Nyame (born 25 December 1955 in the Zing Local Government Area of present-day Taraba State) was Governor of Taraba State in Nigeria from 29 May 1999 to 29 May 2007. He also served as governor of the state from January 1992 to November 1993. He is a member of the then ruling People's Democratic Party (PDP)"</string>

    <string name="danbaba_details">"Danbaba Danfulani Suntai (born 30 June 1961) is a pharmacist who was elected as Executive Governor of Taraba State, Nigeria running for the People's Democratic Party (PDP) in April 2007, and was sworn in on 29 May 2007. He ran successfully for reelection on 26 April 2011.


Danbaba Danfulani Suntai was born on 30 June 1961 at Suntai Town in Bali Local Government Area of Taraba State. He attended Federal Government College, Kano (1975–1980) and the School of Basic Studies at Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria (1980–1981). He was admitted to Ahmadu Bello University where he read Pharmacy and graduated in 1984. He did his internship at Yola Specialist Hospital and his National Youth Service at the State Hospital, Ijaiye, Abeokuta, Ogun State (1985–1986). He then worked at the General Hospital, Ganye in old Gongola State until 1991.

Early political career
Danbaba Suntai was elected Chairman of Bali Local Government (1989–1993). Joining the Taraba State civil service, he was Director-General of the Taraba State Ministry of Agriculture and National Resources (1994–1996). In the 1999 elections, he was State chairman of the All People's Party (APP), when the PDP narrowly defeated the All Nigeria People's Party (ANPP). In 2000, he became Chairman of Taraba State Investment and Properties Ltd. He was appointed Commissioner of the Ministry of Education (2000–2003), and worked at the Ministry of Health (2003–2005) before becoming Secretary to the Taraba State Government (2005–2007).

Governor of Taraba State

Taraba State in Nigeria
In the run-up to the 2007 elections, Danladi Baido won the PDP gubernatorial primaries but was later disqualified. Two months before the election the PDP national secretariat replaced Baido by Danbaba Suntai, who had not stood in the primaries. Baido and lent his support to Suntai, and in April 2007 Suntai won election as Governor of Taraba State. After the elections, relations between Suntai and Baido soured. The unsuccessful Action Congress candidate challenged the switch of PDP candidates and in February 2008 Baido joined this suit. In February 2009 Danladi Baido petitioned the Inspector General of Police, Mike Okiro over alleged SMS messages from Danbaba Suntai threatening to harm him and his family if he continued to appeal the election. In June 2009 Baido claimed that an attempt had been made to assassinate him, linking the incident to the alleged threats.

During his tenure as governor Danbaba Suntai made efforts to fight corruption, crime and lack of discipline, while delegating authority and providing funds to the Local Government Areas. In January 2009 a group of Concerned Indigenes of Taraba State sent a petition to the Economic and Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC) and the Independent Corrupt Practices and Other Related Offences Commission (ICPC), with a copy to President Umaru Yar'Adua, concerning alleged fraudulent financial practices in Suntai's administration. Claims included unnecessary imports of foreign cars, use of foreign rather than local workers, and inflated road building contracts.

In October 2009 Suntai said he strongly supported religious and moral teaching aimed at reducing juvenile delinquency, crime and other vices. He said his administration was strongly behind both the Christian and Islamic faiths since both religions teach peace, love and unity. He initiated reforms to make local government administration more transparent. Among other effects, the monthly pension bill dropped from N33 million to N22 million, while pensioners began getting more regular payments. In November 2009 Danbaba Suntai commissioned a N540 million computerized stone-crushing and asphalt plant to provide road building materials. The plant was constructed by the state government but to be operated on a fully commercial basis.

Suntai ran successfully for reelection on 26 April 2011."</string>

    <string name="danbaba">Danbaba Suntai</string>

    <string name="ddi">Darius Ishaku</string>

    <string name="ddi_details">"Darius Dickson Ishaku (born 30 July 1954) is a Nigerian architect, urban planner, university lecturer and political figure. He is a member of the People's Democratic Party. Ishaku was previously the Minister of State for Niger Delta Affairs before he resigned to contest in the 2015 Taraba State gubernatorial election. Darius won the 2015 election but was in a court battle with his opponent senator Aisha Jumai Alhassan who took to court and after series of case Darius was the declared the winner of the governorship election in the state early this year 2016. He won the initial gubernatorial election and was elected Governor of Taraba State after winning the subsequent re-run election.

EARLY LIFE

Arc Darius dickson ishaku was born on friday 30th day of July 1954 to Mr Ishaku Istifanus and Mrs. Naomi at Lupwe, now in Ussa Local Government Area of Taraba State. He was the fifth of ten childresn and Had a very happy childhood.

The young Darius was Enrolled into St Bartholomew's primary school, Wusasa, Zaria, in 1961, and obtain his first school leaving certificate in 1967.

He then proceed next door to famous St. Paul's College Kufena, Zaria, for his secondary education, in 1972 and passed out in flying colours, obtaining the Almighty West African Examination Certificate(WASC). he then proceed to study Architecture in his B.sc studies."</string>

    <string name="agric_details">The major occupation of the people of Taraba State is agriculture. Cash crops produced in the state include coffee, tea, groundnuts and cotton. Crops such as maize, rice, sorghum, millet, cassava, and yam are also produced in commercial quantity. In addition, cattle, sheep and goats are reared in large numbers, especially on the Mambilla Plateau, and along the Benue and Taraba valleys. Similarly, the people undertake other livestock production activities like poultry production, rabbit breeding and pig farming in fairly large scale. Communities living on the banks of River Benue, River Taraba, River Donga and Ibi engage in fishing all year round. Other occupational activities such as pottery, cloth-weaving, dyeing, mat-making, carving, embroidery and blacksmithing are also carried out in various parts of the State.</string>
    <string name="appbar_scrolling_view_behavior">android.support.design.widget.AppBarLayout$ScrollingViewBehavior</string>
    <string name="ardo">Ardo-Kola</string>
    <string name="ardo_details">"Ardo Kola Local Government Area was created in 1992. Its headquarters is in Sunkani. The local government has an area of 2,262 km² and a population of 86,921 at the 2006 census.
    The major tribes in the local government are Kona, Mumuye, Wurkun, Hausa/Fulani, Yandang while farming is their occupation. A lot of Yam, maize, guinea corn, groundnut, beniseed, cassava, are produced by the inhabitants. The postal code of the area is 660
    "</string>
    <string name="bali">Bali</string>
    <string name="bali_details">Bali Local Government Area was created in 1976. Its headquarters is in Bali.  It has an area of 9,146 km² and a population of 208,935 at the 2006 census. The major tribes are the Ichen, Jibawa, Chamba, Fulani and Kam. The major occupations of the people in Bali are farming, fishing, hunting and rearing of animals. The main crops produced are Yams, rice, Beans, Groundnut, Maize, Melon seeds (brown Equsi) and Sugarcane which are produced in commercial quantities. The postal code of the area is 672</string>
    <string name="bottom_sheet_behavior">android.support.design.widget.BottomSheetBehavior</string>
    <string name="character_counter_pattern">%1$d / %2$d</string>
    <string name="culture_details">"The government has made concerted efforts to improve areas of tourist attractions like Mambilla Tourist Center, Gumpti Park and game reserve in Gashaka; and the Nwunyu Fishing festival in Ibi, which is usually held in April of each year where activities such as canoe racing, swimming competition and cultural dances are held. Other festivals are Purma of the Chamba in Donga, Takum and Bali, the Puje of Jukuns, Kuchecheb ofKutebs in Takum and Ussa, Kati of the Mambilla and host of others. Taraba is called 'Nature's gift to the nation' as the state is rich and have many ethnic groups, including Jenjo, Kuteb Chamba, Mumuyes,Mambila, Wurkums, Fulanis,Jukun,Ichen,Tiv,Kaka, Bandawa, Hausa and Ndoro. A striking historical fact about the State is that it encompasses part of the Mambilla Region which is famed as the Bantu cradle, having been occupied for some five millennia to date (Schwartz, 1972; Zeitlyn Connell, 2003)."</string>
    <string name="donga">Donga</string>
    <string name="donga_details">Donga Local Government Area was created in 1992. Its headquarters is in Donga on the Donga River at 7°43′00″N 10°03′00″E. It has an area of 3,121 km² and a population of 134,111 at the 2006 census. The major tribes in Donga LGA are the Chambas, Jukuns, Ichen and Tiv. The main occupation of the people are fishing, farming, Hunting, caving and petty trading. There are variety of annual cultural festivals in Donga such as Purma of the Chamba and yearly Ichen cultural festival.  The postal code of the area is 671</string>
    <string name="gashaka">Gashaka</string>
    <string name="gashaka_details">Gashaka Local Government Area was created in 1989 with its headquarters in Serti town with an area covering 8,393 km² and a population of 87,781 at the 2006 census. The local government is populated by the Jibawa, Chamba, Fulani, Kuteb, Yandang, Tiv.  The people engage in farming, hunting and animal rearing. Rice, Maize, cassava and guinea corn are the main crops produced. The Gashaka Gumti National park is located in the local government area.  The postal code of the area is 672</string>
    <string name="gassol">Gassol</string>
    <string name="gassol_details">Gassol Local Government Area was created in 1992 with its headquarters in Mutum Biyu.  It has an area of 5,548 km² and a population of 244,749 at the 2006 census.   It is one of the most densely populated local government in the state. Indigenes are mostly farmers, fisher men and petty traders. The land is very fertile and produces large quantities of Yams, Rice, Maize, Groundnut and Melon seeds (brown Equsi) in commercial quantity. The major tribes are Fulani, Tiv, Wurkum and Wurbo, Jukuns. The postal code of the area is 672.</string>
    <string name="geography_details">"Geography

    Taraba State is bounded in the west by Nasarawa State and Benue State, northwest by Plateau State, north by Bauchi State and Gombe State, northeast by Adamawa State, south and east by Cameroon.

    Taraba State lies largely within the middle of Nigeria and consists of undulating landscape dotted with a few mountainous features. These includes the scenic and prominent Mambilla Plateau. The state lies largely within the tropical zone and has a vegetation of low forest in the southern part and grassland in the northern part. The Mambilla Plateau with an altitude of 1,800 meters (6000 ft) above sea level has a temperate climate all year round.

    Rivers Benue, Donga, Taraba and Ibi are the main rivers in the state. They rise from the Cameroonian mountains, straining almost the entire length of the state in the North and South direction to link up with the River Niger."</string>
    <string name="history_details">"Historical Development: Taraba State which comprises the pre1976 divisions of Muri, Mambilla and Wukari, was created

    on 27th August, 1991, along with eight other states by the Federal Military government of the Babangida administration. The state creation exercise was the result of a continuing process of spatio-political devolution, which started in 1963, to make Nigeria a politically stable and economically strong country.

    Taraba State, with its numerous small ethnic groups and remote location, was a particularly neglected and grossly underdeveloped part of the former Gongola State. Because of its rugged topography, lack of access roads from other parts of the country, and indeed, the neglect it suffered from past administrations, the state still remains largely peripheral to the nation's economic and political life.

    The need to diffuse centres of economic growth and draw the peripheral population into the mainstream of the nation's economy, which are among the important reasons adduced to justify state creation exercises in the country, are therefore most relevant to Taraba State.

    With an estimated land area of about 54,428 sq. km, the state lies roughly between latitudes 6Â°25'N and 9Â°30'N and between longitudes 9Â°30'E and 11Â°45'E. It is bordered on the west by Gombe and Plateau States, and by Adamawa State to the northeast. It also shares its southwestern boundary with Benue State. An international boundary on the east, separates Taraba State from the Republic of Cameroun.

    Administrative Areas: To achieve the objectives of spatiopolitical devolution, Taraba State was subdivided into twelve Local Government Areas (LGA) at the time of its creation (in 1991). These include Bali, Dondga, Gashaka, Ibi, Jalingo, Karim Lamido, Lau, Sardauna, Takum, Wukari, Yorro and Zing. In 1996, three new local government areas namely Ardo Kola, Kurmi and Ussa, were carved out of Bali, Takum, and Jalingo LGAs respectively.

    This brings the number of administrative units to sixteen currently. These are further subdivided into eighteen district areas. The district areas are units based essentially on cultural factors which seek to emphasize ethnic circumstances. Unlike the local government units which officially operate and are recognized as the third tier of government, the districts are administered traditionally through a hierarchy of chiefs, village and ward heads.

    The traditional setup of the district level administration serves as an important linkage between the grassroots population and the local government administration. This arrangement, though not sufficiently exploited yet, has no doubt helped to enhance peace and harmony among the various ethnic groups in the state.

    Perhaps it may be necessary to allude that the future spatial plan ning for development in Taraba State should encourage the reemergence and proper integration of the districts or a system of development areas in each local government area, as an integral part of a grassroot based development strategy that recognizes the fourth dimension administrative structure."</string>
    <string name="ibi">Ibi</string>
    <string name="ibi_details">Ibi Local Government Area of Taraba State, Nigeria was created in 1992.Its headquarters is Ibi town which is located on the south bank of the Benue River, opposite the influx of the much smaller Shemankar River. Both the Taraba River and the Donga River flow into the Benue within the LGA. Ibi was part of the Jukun kingdom (1720-1815) whose capital, Kororofa, was 35 miles east (up river). After the Fulani invasion Ibi became part of the Muri Emirate (1817-1892). Like the rest of Muri it was under the French governor Louis Mizon from 18921893.</string>
    <string name="jalingo">Jalingo</string>
    <string name="jalingo_details">Jalingo is a city in north-eastern Nigeria. It is the capital city of Taraba State and has an estimated population of 118,000. It is the seat of the government of Taraba state, seat of Muri emirate. Tribes in the local government include Kona, Fulani, Mumuye with a cosmopolitan coloration. Business, trading and civil service are the main occupation of the area.</string>
    <string name="karim">Karim-LAmido</string>
    <string name="karim_details">Karim Lamido Local Government Area was created in 1976 and has an area of 6,620 km² and a population of 195,844 at the 2006 census.The southern border of Karin Lamido is the Benue River and it is traversed by several tributaries of that river. The major tribes are Wurkun, Jenjo, Karinjo, Bandawa, Bikwin who engages in farming, fishing and animal husbandry. The postal code of the area is 662</string>
    <string name="kurmi">Kurmi</string>
    <string name="kurmi_details">Kurmi Local Government Area was created in 1992 with its headquarters in the town of Ba’issa. It has an area of 4,353 km² and a population of 91,531 according to 2006 census. The major tribes are Ndoro, Tigun and Ichen while their main occupations of the people farming and hunting. Palm oil, plantain, oranges and Banana are found in commercial quantities. The postal code of the area is 671</string>
    <string name="lau">Lau</string>
    <string name="lau_details">Lau Local Government Area with Lau as Its headquarters. It has an area of 1,660 km² and a population of 96,590 at the 2006 census. The local government was created in 1989, The major tribes include Yandang, Mumuye, Hausa/Fulani, Jenjo, Bakula, Kunini and Lau Habe Farming is the major preoccupation of the people with Guinea corn, Maize, cotton, rice, yam, beans as the stable crops while animal husbandry and fishing is also a pastime. The postal code of the area is 662.</string>
    <string name="lga">Local Government Area</string>
    <string name="overview">Overview</string>
    <string name="pastg">Past and Present Governors</string>
    <string name="sardauna">Sardauna</string>
    <string name="sardauna_details">Sardauna Local Government Area is located in the extreme southeast of Taraba State in Nigeria. It sits atop the Mambilla Plateau, which is dotted by other towns such as Maisamari and Nguroje. The capital of the LGA is Gembu, which is the principal town of various ethnic groups, such as Mambilla, Fulani, Kaka, Kambu, and Panso. Other ethnic groups from the mainstream Nigeria and the bordering Cameroon republic such as Hausa and Kanuri also live there. Farming and rearing of livestock is their pastime. Herds of cows sprawls the undulating hills while pear, banana, maize, cassava, tea and coffee are the main stables of the area. In contrast to the rather steamy and humid climate of most other parts of southeastern Nigeria, the climate in this part of the country (owing to its altitude) is relatively cool; most days in the dry season the temperature will reach 20-23 C and drop to 16-18 C at night, whilst in the wet season these averages fall a couple of degrees. The area is a tourist attraction.</string>
    <string name="senators">"Sen. Sani Abubakar Danladi,
    Sen. Yusuf Abubakar Yusuf,
    Sen. Emmanuel Bwacha"</string>
    <string name="takum">Takum</string>
    <string name="takum_details">Takum Local Government Area in Taraba State, Nigeria was created in 1976. Its headquarters are in the town of Takum. Takum borders the Republic of Cameroon in the south. It has an area of 2,503 km² and a population of 135,349 at the 2006 census. The local government is populated by Chamba, Jukun, Kuteb and Ichen. Farming is the people’s pastime. Major crops include cereals, roots and fruits among which are Maize, rice, guinea corn, yam, cassava, oranges, banana, cashew, mango, palm oil The postal code of the area is 671</string>
    <string name="ussa_details">Ussa Local Government Area in Taraba State, Nigeria has its headquarters in Lissam. Ussa borders the Republic of Cameroon in the south; the Donga River forms its northern boundary. It is a monolithic community with Kutebs as the tribe. Hunting and crop production include cereals, roots and fruits among which are Maize, rice, guinea corn, yam, cassava, oranges, banana, cashew, mango, palm oil are the people’s preoccupation It has an area of 1,495 km² and a population of 92,017 at the 2006 census and was created in 1992. The postal code of the area is 671</string>
    <string name="weather">"
 &lt;b&gt;Weather/Climate&lt;/b&gt; Like most parts of northern Nigeria, Taraba State has a wet and dry climate; the wet season lasts, on the average, from April to October with mean annual rainfall that varies between 1058mm in the north around Jalingo and Zing, to over 1300mm in the South around Serti and Takum. The wettest months are August and September. The dry season lasts from November to March; the driest months are December and January with relative humidity dropping to about 15 percent. Mean annual temperature around Jalingo is about 28°C with maximum temperatures varying between 30°C and 39.4°C, and minimum temperatures range between 15°C to 23°C. The Mambilla plateau has climatic characteristics typical of a temperate climate. "</string>
    <string name="wukari">Wukari</string>
    <string name="wukari_deatils">Wukari Local Government Area in Taraba State, Nigeria. Its headquarters is in the town of Wukari on the A4 highway. The local government was created in 1976. The Donga River flows through the area and the Benue River forms a boundary with Nasarawa State to the northwest. The town is the base of the Wukari Federation, a traditional state. It has an area of 4,308 km² and a population of 241,546 at the 2006 census. The postal code of the area is 670</string>
    <string name="yoro">Yoro</string>
    <string name="yoro_deatails">Yorro Local Government Area in Taraba State, Nigeria has its headquarters in Pantisawa covering an area of 1,275 km² and a population of 89,410 at the 2006 census. The people here are Mumuye predominantly and they are farmers and hunters. Yam, groundnut, maize, cassava, rice, bambara nuts are the products of their farms, while goats, sheep and fowls are the animals reared in this area. The postal code of the area is 661</string>
    <string name="zing">Zing</string>
    <string name="zing_details">Zing Local Government Area in Taraba State, Nigeria has its headquarters in Zing with an area of 1,030 km² and a population of 127,363 at the 2006 census. 98% of the people in Zing are predominantly mumuye with twelve [12] clans. The postal code of the area is 661</string>
    <string name="ussa">Ussa</string>
    <string name="image_chooser">File Chooser</string>
    <string name="title_activity_scrolling">ScrollingActivity</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>


</resources>
